<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ccc on xenol&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/tags/ccc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ccc on xenol&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 15:39:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.xenol.eu/tags/ccc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Refreshing Memories: report from 35c3</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2019/01/22/Refreshing-Memories-report-from-35c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 15:39:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2019/01/22/Refreshing-Memories-report-from-35c3/</guid>
      <description>This blog post will summarize my experience attending 35th Chaos Communication Congress AKA 35c3, which took place between 27th and 30th December 2018 in Leipzig, Germany. The Congress hosts a variety of talks, assemblies and serves as a meeting point for thousands of people from the security and hackerspace communities. Moreover, the Congress covers many other different topics ranging from arts &amp;amp; culture, technology, hobby projects as well as politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34C3: Tuwat!</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2018/01/14/34C3-Tuwat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 15:39:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2018/01/14/34C3-Tuwat/</guid>
      <description>New location AKA Willkommen in Leipzig My first visit to 29C3 in 2012 was the year when Congress moved from Berlin to Hamburg. Bigger auditoriums, more room for more people. After the last year&amp;rsquo;s problems with almost 2000 people not getting to 33C3 because of the congress hall capacity limits, CCC organizers decided to look for a new venue. They found one in the city of Leipzig and Congress Hall Leipzig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33C3: Works for me</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/01/02/33C3-Works-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 20:39:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/01/02/33C3-Works-for-me/</guid>
      <description>I visited 33rd Chaos Communication Congress, which took place between 27th and 30th December 2016 in CCH in Hamburg. The motto of last year&amp;rsquo;s congress was Works for me. This was my fifth attendance of the Chaos Communication Congress.
The overall atmosphere on the Congress and organization was excellent as always. However, I have to admit that the quallity of talks was worse when compared to previous years. During previous Congresses I had problems with choosing which talk to attend as there were too many of them I wanted to visit at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Finale</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/31/29c3-finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/31/29c3-finale/</guid>
      <description>I arrived at CCH in the afternoon and headed directly for NOC Review talk. Guys did really wonderful job, although the Wifi was a problem. I really liked some network facts:
 ~70 access points, great signal coverage 3059 concurrent wireless clients connected during peaks traffic usage of 8.2 Gbps 40% of traffic being IPv6  Video can be found here.
The 29C3 was really nice experience and I will definitely return back to 30C3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day Three</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/30/29c3-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/30/29c3-day-three/</guid>
      <description>Third day of the Congress was filled with some number of interesting talks I visited. I started with a talk, in which I was interested the most - An Overview of Secure Name Resolution - DNSSEC, DNSCurve and Namecoin. Speaker gave great introduction into DNSSEC and also talked about its deployment rate. He also spoke DNSSEC&amp;rsquo;s use in amplification attacks and suitable countermeasures. DNSCurve and Namecoin was discussed as well. From this talk, it is clear that DNSSEC is the way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day Two</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/29/29c3-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/29/29c3-day-two/</guid>
      <description>I started this day with visiting talk by Axel Arnbak titled Certificate Authority Collapse. Axel talked about the current model being completely broken (nothing new in the security community) and that the change is needed. He described the DigiNotar incident. The European Union wants to address this issue by regulations, which do more harm than good. If the CA model is broken, it should be fixed technically and not by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day One</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/28/29c3-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/28/29c3-day-one/</guid>
      <description>29c3 is my first Congress I visited. It returned to Hamburg after 8 years of being held in Berlin and is located at the Conference Center Hamburg (CCH). First day&amp;rsquo;s talk were mostly non-technical ones.
Not my department by Jacob Appelbaum proposed that people should develop more software like Tor or similiar tools.
The second talk titled Enemies of the State: What Happens When Telling the Truth about Secret US Government Power Becomes a Crime was about breaking the US constitution by the US goverment and the rise of spying practices after 11th September 2001 covered as the fight against the terrorism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>