<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ccc on xenol&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenol.eu/tags/ccc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ccc on xenol&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenol.eu/tags/ccc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Finale</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/31/29c3-finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/31/29c3-finale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived at CCH in the afternoon and headed directly for &lt;strong&gt;NOC Review&lt;/strong&gt; talk. Guys did really wonderful job, although the Wifi was a problem. I really liked some network facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~70 access points, great signal coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3059 concurrent wireless clients connected during peaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;traffic usage of 8.2 Gbps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40% of traffic being IPv6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftp.uni-kl.de/CCC/29C3/mp4-h264-HQ/29c3-5404-en-noc_review_h264.mp4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 29C3 was really nice experience and I will definitely return back to 30C3. Another nice thing was that event of this size was run entirely by the volunteers. I would like to take part in helping as a Chaos Angel or directly as a speaker next year. We will see what will 2013 bring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day Three</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/30/29c3-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/30/29c3-day-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Third day of the Congress was filled with some number of interesting talks I visited. I started with a talk, in which I was interested the most - &lt;strong&gt;An Overview of Secure Name Resolution - DNSSEC, DNSCurve and Namecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. Speaker gave great introduction into DNSSEC and also talked about its deployment rate. He also spoke DNSSEC&amp;rsquo;s use in amplification attacks and suitable countermeasures. DNSCurve and Namecoin was discussed as well. From this talk, it is clear that DNSSEC is the way forward. Video will be available shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Evaluation of Russian GOST Cipher&lt;/strong&gt; gave nice overview of Russian GOST cipher and it&amp;rsquo;s history. In theory, GOST should be secure for 200 more years. I am a bit sceptic as in the last two years there were found around 20+ possible attacks on GOST. Speaker talked about them and described the steps how to attack. Video will be available shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great talk by Daniel J. Bernstein was titled &lt;strong&gt;Hash-flooding DoS reloaded: attacks and defenses&lt;/strong&gt;. Dan explained hash tables and described anatomy of the hash flooding attacks in detail. Martin Boßlet demonstrated vulnerability on languages using MurmurHash as a hashing function. He used Ruby and Java for demonstrating purposes. Martin spoke about better alternatives - &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/cityhash/&#34;&gt;CityHash&lt;/a&gt; by Google. However, he demonstrated that it is worse than MurmurHash family of hash functions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://131002.net/siphash/&#34;&gt;SipHash&lt;/a&gt; was introduced as a simple, yet secure alternative. Video will be available shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day Two</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/29/29c3-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/29/29c3-day-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this day with visiting talk by Axel Arnbak titled &lt;strong&gt;Certificate Authority Collapse&lt;/strong&gt;. Axel talked about the current model being completely broken (nothing new in the security community) and that the change is needed. He described the DigiNotar incident. The European Union wants to address this issue by &lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/information_society/policy/esignature/eu_legislation/regulation/index_en.htm&#34;&gt;regulations&lt;/a&gt;, which do more harm than good. If the CA model is broken, it should be fixed technically and not by law. Video can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftp.uni-kl.de/CCC/29C3/mp4-h264-HQ/29c3-5319-en-certificate_authority_collapse_h264.mp4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, I went and saw &lt;strong&gt;Lightning talks&lt;/strong&gt; block. I liked the talk about a &lt;a href=&#34;rhizomatica.org&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; building community GSM and mesh networks in remote areas in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great talk of the day was &lt;strong&gt;FactHacks - RSA factorization in the real world&lt;/strong&gt; by Daniel J. Bernstein, Nadia Heninger and Tanja Lange. Speakers gave a quick introduction to RSA cryptosystem and some facts about its factorization. Dan also showed several &lt;a href=&#34;facthacks.cr.yp.to&#34;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt; for factoring primes. There was practical example on how  we can search for private keys on the Internet, complete missing parts of it and speakers generally advised to &lt;strong&gt;stop using 1024-bits RSA keys&lt;/strong&gt;. I switched to ECDSA few months ago and you should do it as well. If your SSH server doesn&amp;rsquo;t support ECDSA (OpenSSH &amp;lt;5.7), then stick to 2048 bit or 4096 bit private key size. Video can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftp.uni-kl.de/CCC/29C3/mp4-h264-HQ/29c3-5275-en-facthacks_h264.mp4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final talk I visited was about &lt;strong&gt;Stylometry and Online Underground Markets&lt;/strong&gt;, which was about the usage of stylometry to identify and gaining a better understanding of how do underground market work. Video should be available shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day One</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/28/29c3-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/28/29c3-day-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;29c3 is my first Congress I visited. It returned to Hamburg after 8 years of being held in Berlin and is located at the Conference Center Hamburg (CCH). First day&amp;rsquo;s talk were mostly non-technical ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not my department&lt;/strong&gt; by Jacob Appelbaum proposed that people should develop more software like Tor or similiar tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second talk titled &lt;strong&gt;Enemies of the State: What Happens When Telling the Truth about Secret US Government Power Becomes a Crime&lt;/strong&gt; was about breaking the US constitution by the US goverment and the rise of spying practices after 11th September 2001 covered as the fight against the terrorism. Speakers talked about ways how NSA wants to monitor people and store everything they can about them. They also suggested that people should care more about their privacy. After all, anonymity and privacy are the basic right of the every human being on the planet. This talk was given by ex-employees of NSA and US DoJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last talk I visited was about the mitigation of timing side channels by Sebastian Schinzel. He proposed several new countermeasures and wrote set of tools, which should detect timing side channels vulnerabilities. More info can be found on his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seecurity.org/29c3/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the last talk, I returned to the hostel and drunk mate with Juraj. Rest of the group joined us later and several polish hackers came as well. Discussions were mostly security-related.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>