<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xenol&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on xenol&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.xenol.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The day when I stopped worrying about exposed SSH ports! - WoSECxGlovo (EN)</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2020/08/20/The-day-when-I-stopped-worrying-about-exposed-SSH-ports-WoSECxGlovo-EN/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2020/08/20/The-day-when-I-stopped-worrying-about-exposed-SSH-ports-WoSECxGlovo-EN/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://youtu.be/OAJItJgvf4Q?t=310</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scapy Workshop - NetBCN (EN)</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2020/06/11/Scapy-Workshop-NetBCN-EN/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2020/06/11/Scapy-Workshop-NetBCN-EN/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://youtu.be/yYbIcElSGOg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a good colleague and help your Security Engineer! - PyconES 2019 (EN)</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2019/10/05/Be-a-good-colleague-and-help-your-Security-Engineer-PyconES-2019-EN/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2019/10/05/Be-a-good-colleague-and-help-your-Security-Engineer-PyconES-2019-EN/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://youtu.be/7FZQaEYZspk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security tooling for Pythonistas - Python Meetup BA (SK)</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2019/10/05/Security-tooling-for-Pythonistas-Python-Meetup-BA-SK/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2019/10/05/Security-tooling-for-Pythonistas-Python-Meetup-BA-SK/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a good colleague and help your Security Engineer! - PyconSK 2019 (EN)</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2019/03/22/Be-a-good-colleague-and-help-your-Security-Engineer-PyconSK-2019-EN/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2019/03/22/Be-a-good-colleague-and-help-your-Security-Engineer-PyconSK-2019-EN/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://youtu.be/2NwqC4e8X-c</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refreshing Memories: report from 35c3</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2019/01/22/Refreshing-Memories-report-from-35c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 15:39:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2019/01/22/Refreshing-Memories-report-from-35c3/</guid>
      <description>This blog post will summarize my experience attending 35th Chaos Communication Congress AKA 35c3, which took place between 27th and 30th December 2018 in Leipzig, Germany. The Congress hosts a variety of talks, assemblies and serves as a meeting point for thousands of people from the security and hackerspace communities. Moreover, the Congress covers many other different topics ranging from arts &amp;amp; culture, technology, hobby projects as well as politics. In this post, I will be mainly focusing on the security and technical talks of the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34C3: Tuwat!</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2018/01/14/34C3-Tuwat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 15:39:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2018/01/14/34C3-Tuwat/</guid>
      <description>New location AKA Willkommen in Leipzig My first visit to 29C3 in 2012 was the year when Congress moved from Berlin to Hamburg. Bigger auditoriums, more room for more people. After the last year&amp;rsquo;s problems with almost 2000 people not getting to 33C3 because of the congress hall capacity limits, CCC organizers decided to look for a new venue. They found one in the city of Leipzig and Congress Hall Leipzig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing more illumos networking with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/02/11/Managing-more-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 21:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/02/11/Managing-more-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</guid>
      <description>On January 9th, the rest of my work on Ansible modules for managing Solaris/illumos networking was accepted into Ansible and this work will be a part of the next release. With this batch of modules almost every aspect of Solaris/illumos networking (apart from link aggregations and bridges) can be configured and managed by Ansible. The following new modules are available in Ansible:
 dladm_vlan dladm_linkprop dladm_iptun ipadm_addr ipadm_addrprop ipadm_ifprop  In the next blog post I will show some real examples how to accomplish useful work with these modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33C3: Works for me</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/01/02/33C3-Works-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 20:39:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/01/02/33C3-Works-for-me/</guid>
      <description>I visited 33rd Chaos Communication Congress, which took place between 27th and 30th December 2016 in CCH in Hamburg. The motto of last year&amp;rsquo;s congress was Works for me. This was my fifth attendance of the Chaos Communication Congress.
The overall atmosphere on the Congress and organization was excellent as always. However, I have to admit that the quallity of talks was worse when compared to previous years. During previous Congresses I had problems with choosing which talk to attend as there were too many of them I wanted to visit at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing illumos networking with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/09/03/Managing-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 12:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/09/03/Managing-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</guid>
      <description>On August 30th, my work on Ansible modules for managing Solaris/illumos networking was merged into ansible-modules-extras repository. This functionality will be available in the next release of Ansible. Following modules were contributed:
 dladm_etherstub dladm_vnic ipadm_if ipadm_prop flowadm  This also marks a major milestone for automating the deployment of Solaris/illumos zones with Ansible. There already was a module for creating/deleting zones and manipulating their state - solaris_zone. However, there was not a way to manage the networking aspect of zones until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirroring OpenIndiana IPS repositories - part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/08/09/Mirroring-OpenIndiana-IPS-repositories-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:09:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/08/09/Mirroring-OpenIndiana-IPS-repositories-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this blog post, I will show how one can create a mirror of OpenIndiana IPS repositories. IPS repositories hold packages coming from multiple sources, most notably from illumos-gate and oi-userland. Every time user runs pkg update on his OpenIndiana installation, pkg contacts IPS repository to fetch catalog metadata and determines if there are any new updates available. If updates are available, pkg downoalds only changed files over HTTP. IPS application server is written in Python and CherryPy web framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration from Octopress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/07/04/Migration-from-Octopress-to-Hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 02:54:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/07/04/Migration-from-Octopress-to-Hugo/</guid>
      <description>After a while, my blog finally received love it deserved. The biggest change is that I migrated the blog from Octopress to Hugo, which is a fast static site generator written in Go. The overall feeling stayed the same, but the blog maintenance is much easier for me. I am still finding my way around Hugo, but so far it works nicely. Another change is that this site is being hosted on Github Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Finale</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/31/29c3-finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/31/29c3-finale/</guid>
      <description>I arrived at CCH in the afternoon and headed directly for NOC Review talk. Guys did really wonderful job, although the Wifi was a problem. I really liked some network facts:
 ~70 access points, great signal coverage 3059 concurrent wireless clients connected during peaks traffic usage of 8.2 Gbps 40% of traffic being IPv6  Video can be found here.
The 29C3 was really nice experience and I will definitely return back to 30C3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day Three</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/30/29c3-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/30/29c3-day-three/</guid>
      <description>Third day of the Congress was filled with some number of interesting talks I visited. I started with a talk, in which I was interested the most - An Overview of Secure Name Resolution - DNSSEC, DNSCurve and Namecoin. Speaker gave great introduction into DNSSEC and also talked about its deployment rate. He also spoke DNSSEC&amp;rsquo;s use in amplification attacks and suitable countermeasures. DNSCurve and Namecoin was discussed as well. From this talk, it is clear that DNSSEC is the way forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day Two</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/29/29c3-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/29/29c3-day-two/</guid>
      <description>I started this day with visiting talk by Axel Arnbak titled Certificate Authority Collapse. Axel talked about the current model being completely broken (nothing new in the security community) and that the change is needed. He described the DigiNotar incident. The European Union wants to address this issue by regulations, which do more harm than good. If the CA model is broken, it should be fixed technically and not by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29c3: Day One</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/28/29c3-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/12/28/29c3-day-one/</guid>
      <description>29c3 is my first Congress I visited. It returned to Hamburg after 8 years of being held in Berlin and is located at the Conference Center Hamburg (CCH). First day&amp;rsquo;s talk were mostly non-technical ones.
Not my department by Jacob Appelbaum proposed that people should develop more software like Tor or similiar tools.
The second talk titled Enemies of the State: What Happens When Telling the Truth about Secret US Government Power Becomes a Crime was about breaking the US constitution by the US goverment and the rise of spying practices after 11th September 2001 covered as the fight against the terrorism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNSSEC automatization with OpenDNSSEC</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/10/29/dnssec-automatization-with-opendnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/10/29/dnssec-automatization-with-opendnssec/</guid>
      <description>DNSSEC is an amazing piece of technology. DNSSEC data is digitally signed. The validating DNS server can check if the data it receives is identical to those on the authoritative DNS server. This helps us mitigate DNS cache poisoning.
I have signed my domain back in January 2012, signing my zone by hand. However, I forgot to resign my zone and the zone signature expired making it unresolvable. This made me wonder how could I automatize the whole process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed RHCE exam</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/06/01/passed-rhce-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/06/01/passed-rhce-exam/</guid>
      <description>I took and passed both Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) and Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE) exams. The certification is valid for 3 years. After that you have to either retake RHCE exam or pass other higher level Red Hat certification in order to prolong certification validity. RHCSA exam took 2.5 hours and RHCE 2 hours. I was nearly done after 1 hour and used the remaining time for checking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Adam and I enjoy playing with technology. I studied computer networks at the Faculty of Informatics and Information Technologies at Slovak University of Technology in Bratislava.
When I was 14, I started playing with UNIX-like operating systems and never stopped since then. In my free time, I try to contribute to various open source projects or experiment with technology. Whenever I have to code, I do all my projects in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenIndiana involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/02/11/openindiana-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/02/11/openindiana-involvement/</guid>
      <description>I have been watching OpenSolaris development for a long time. As a technology fan, I really like all the cool features OpenSolaris offers: ZFS filesystem capabilities, service management with SMF, dynamic tracing and application debugging with DTrace, container-based virtualization with Solaris zones, network virtualization with Crossbow, safe system upgrades and downtime minimalization via Boot Environments and integratiom of all these features together makes it perfect operating system for a server. However, OpenSolaris is dead and it continues to live as OpenIndiana, which is a Illumos-based derivate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy FreeBSD jail management with ZFS and pkgng</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/02/04/easy-freebsd-jail-management-with-zfs-and-pkgng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/02/04/easy-freebsd-jail-management-with-zfs-and-pkgng/</guid>
      <description>I have been using FreeBSD jails ever since I started using FreeBSD on my servers. Jail can be described as a chroot on steroids with own users, process namespace and lately own virtualized network stack.
I am using FreeBSD jails for mainly for securing and separating services. Each service runs in its own separated container on its own ZFS dataset. Each dataset is a ZFS clone from the snapshot of the template jail, which is adapted to have software I need in every jail installed (zsh, git, vim&amp;hellip;) and configured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/01/06/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/01/06/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal blog! I had an idea of creating personal blog for a very long time. However, I was always lazy to do so.
When I was looking for some blogging engine, I realized that none of the major ones suited me. So I started to experiment with various setups and then I discovered jekyll, which is static blog generator. I like the idea of having a blog completely stored in version control of my choice and served as static pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to DNSSEC (SK)</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2011/09/13/Introduction-to-DNSSEC-SK/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talk/2011/09/13/Introduction-to-DNSSEC-SK/</guid>
      <description>Link: https://youtu.be/8ewJ7caEA5U</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
