<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freebsd on xenol&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/tags/freebsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freebsd on xenol&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.xenol.eu/tags/freebsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DNSSEC automatization with OpenDNSSEC</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/10/29/dnssec-automatization-with-opendnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/10/29/dnssec-automatization-with-opendnssec/</guid>
      <description>DNSSEC is an amazing piece of technology. DNSSEC data is digitally signed. The validating DNS server can check if the data it receives is identical to those on the authoritative DNS server. This helps us mitigate DNS cache poisoning.
I have signed my domain back in January 2012, signing my zone by hand. However, I forgot to resign my zone and the zone signature expired making it unresolvable. This made me wonder how could I automatize the whole process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy FreeBSD jail management with ZFS and pkgng</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/02/04/easy-freebsd-jail-management-with-zfs-and-pkgng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/2012/02/04/easy-freebsd-jail-management-with-zfs-and-pkgng/</guid>
      <description>I have been using FreeBSD jails ever since I started using FreeBSD on my servers. Jail can be described as a chroot on steroids with own users, process namespace and lately own virtualized network stack.
I am using FreeBSD jails for mainly for securing and separating services. Each service runs in its own separated container on its own ZFS dataset. Each dataset is a ZFS clone from the snapshot of the template jail, which is adapted to have software I need in every jail installed (zsh, git, vim&amp;hellip;) and configured.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>