<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ansible on xenol&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/tags/ansible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ansible on xenol&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 21:41:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.xenol.eu/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible modules and OpenIndiana</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/02/12/Ansible-modules-and-OpenIndiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 21:41:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/02/12/Ansible-modules-and-OpenIndiana/</guid>
      <description>Preface Ansible is a great software for automating and managing systems. In this blog post I will post some examples how to use Ansible modules for accomplishing various tasks on OpenIndiana.
Package and package repository management Install IPS packages - name: Install common packages pkg5: name: - tcpdump - tmux - shells/zsh state=present  Remove IPS packages - name: Remove tcpdump pkg5: name=tcpdump state=absent  Remove IPS publisher - name: Remove openindiana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing more illumos networking with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/02/11/Managing-more-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 21:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2017/02/11/Managing-more-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</guid>
      <description>On January 9th, the rest of my work on Ansible modules for managing Solaris/illumos networking was accepted into Ansible and this work will be a part of the next release. With this batch of modules almost every aspect of Solaris/illumos networking (apart from link aggregations and bridges) can be configured and managed by Ansible. The following new modules are available in Ansible:
 dladm_vlan dladm_linkprop dladm_iptun ipadm_addr ipadm_addrprop ipadm_ifprop  In the next blog post I will show some real examples how to accomplish useful work with these modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing illumos networking with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/09/03/Managing-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 12:10:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.xenol.eu/blog/2016/09/03/Managing-illumos-networking-with-Ansible/</guid>
      <description>On August 30th, my work on Ansible modules for managing Solaris/illumos networking was merged into ansible-modules-extras repository. This functionality will be available in the next release of Ansible. Following modules were contributed:
 dladm_etherstub dladm_vnic ipadm_if ipadm_prop flowadm  This also marks a major milestone for automating the deployment of Solaris/illumos zones with Ansible. There already was a module for creating/deleting zones and manipulating their state - solaris_zone. However, there was not a way to manage the networking aspect of zones until now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>